A Guide to the Rockefeller Foundation records, projects, SG 1.2, Series 300 Latin America - Series 833 Lebanon FA387b
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller Foundation records, projects, SG 1.2, Series 300 Latin America - Series 833 Lebanon
1910-2000
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller Foundation
FA387b
402.19 Cubic Feet
Biographical/Historical note
The Rockefeller Foundation was established by act of the New York State Legislature approved by the Governor on May 14, 1913, "to promote the well-being of mankind throughout the world." Between 1913 and 1928 the China Medical Board, the International Health Board, and the Division of Medical Education functioned as divisions of the Foundation, concentrating on the administration of programs in public health and medical education. A Division of Studies was created in 1923 to handle projects outside the medical field. These early years were experimental as the new foundation studied the methods of philanthropy and explored its relationships with other Rockefeller boards.
Although the Rockefeller Foundation is the largest and best known philanthropy founded by the Rockefeller family, it was neither the first nor the last to be established. The Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research (1901), the General Education Board (1902), the Rockefeller Sanitary Commission for the Eradication of Hookworm Disease (1909), and the Bureau of Social Hygiene (1911) all existed earlier. When the Foundation was created, the Sanitary Commission was disbanded. After the establishment of the Foundation, the Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial (1918) and the International Education Board (1923) were created.
The Rockefeller boards and their programs were reconsidered and reorganized in 1927-1928 in order to avoid overlapping programs. The International Health Board of the Foundation was disbanded and an International Health Division was organized. The China Medical Board, Inc., was established as a separately incorporated institution, and the China Medical Board of the Foundation ceased to exist. The Division of Studies was dropped and the Division of Medical Education was phased out. The Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial was combined with the Foundation and the Spelman Fund of New York was chartered to continue activities of the LSRM that were not absorbed by the Foundation. The International Education Board was disbanded.
As a result of this reorganization, the Foundation adopted a program which included public health work (administered by the IHD), the advancement of knowledge in the medical and natural sciences (in part taken over from the IEB), the social sciences (formerly the field of the LSRM), and the humanities and arts (shared with the GEB). The Rockefeller Institute and the Bureau of Social Hygiene were not affected by the reorganization. The program adopted by the Foundation at this time remained basically the same for the next twenty years.
As its files accumulated, the Foundation maintained a card index recording the names of institutional and individual grantees and correspondents. A microfilm copy of this index is available at the Archive Center.
Arrangement note
The project files are arranged in series according to country. Each country or geographical area was assigned a three-digit number by RF staff. In addition, letters signifying program areas are used: for example, "A" indicates a grant in the Medical Sciences, and "C" Nursing. Material is organized within these letter/program subdivisions alphabetically by grant title. A grant title usually consists of a heading that includes the name of the institution or individual that received the grant. Thus each grant, or project, is filed individually in one or more folders.
File Plan note
RG 1.1, 1.2, and part of 1.3
Organization of the Rockefeller Foundation's archives:
RG 1 Projects
RG 2 General Correspondence
RG 3 Administration, Program and Policy
RG 4 China Medical Board
RG 5 International Health Board/Division
RG 6 Field Offices
RG 7 Treasurer's Office
RG 8 Comptroller
RG 9 Personnel
RG 10 Fellowships
RG 11 Information Services
RG 12 Diaries
RG 13 Oral Histories
RG 14 Counsel
RG 15 Secretary
RG 16 Minutes and Officers Actions
RG 17 Dockets
RG 18 Declinations (100F)
RG 19 Non-textual Materials
RG 20 Communications Office
Conditions Governing Access note
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Confidential material in this record group has been segregated and is inaccessible. Each pertinent file is open to research, and physical removal of the segregated material within each file is not necessary.
Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Scope and Contents
Types of records include: project files.
War relief; Tuberculosis; Viruses -- Research; Agriculture; Nursing; Diseases; Arts; Hookworm disease; Epidemiology; Philanthropy; Humanities; Hospitals; Scholarships; Social sciences -- Scholarships, fellowships, etc.; Respiratory organs -- Diseases; Scarlatina -- Hospitals -- Administration; Public health administration; Public health -- Scholarships, fellowships, etc.; Public health; Humanities -- Scholarships, fellowships, etc.; Life sciences; Malaria; Medical care; Medical sciences; Natural history; Yaws; Yellow fever
- Latin America, 1920-1973; 300; 6.4 Cubic Feet; 16 __Boxes __6.4 cubic feet
  Arrangement note
  Divided into 5 subseries as follows: 300 A Medical Science 300 D Natural Science 300 R Humanities and arts 300 S Social Sciences 300 V Virus Studies
  - Latin America - General (No Program), 300.GEN
    - HAY Hayes, Guy S. "Diary of a Trip to Brazil and Peru", November 3-22, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 0000A)
    - Inter-American Institute of Americultural Sciences - Agricultural Sciences in Latin America - (Alfonson Castronova, Book Publication), 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Maize Preservation - (National Research Council Project), 1949-1963, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 2-6)
    - Program and Policy, 1938-1948 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Program and Policy, 1950, 1952-1957, 1959-1963, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - (Program and Policy) - Pro-1 - "Rockefeller Foundation Appropriations to Latin America", July 1, 1913 - June 30, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - (Program and Policy) - PRO-2, 3, 4, 4a, 4b (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - (Program and Policy) - PRO-5, 6, 7 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - (Program and Policy) - Inter-Divisional Committee, 1943-1948 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - (Program and Policy) - (Inter-Divisional Committee) - Minutes, Reports Statements - PRO - INT-1, November 29, 1943-January 31, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - (Program and Policy) - International Health Division, 1920, 1938-1943, 1946-1948, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - (Program and Policy) - International Health Division "Memorandum on the Work of the International Health Division in the West Indies and Latin America, 1913-1941" (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Latin America - Medical Science, 300.A
    - Medical Education - (no grant made), 1915-1916, 1954-1956 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Bauer, J. H. - Med Surv-1 - A Survey of Medical Education in Chile, May 1952 (Box 002A, Folder 0016A)
    - Bauer, J. H. - Med Surv-2,3,4, - A Survey of Medical Education in Ecuador,... Bolivia,... Peru, August-September 1952 (Box 002A, Folder 0016B)
    - Bauer, J. H. - Med Surv-5, - A Survey of Medical Education in Colombia, December 1952 (Box 002A, Folder 0016C)
    - Bauer, J. H. - Med Surv-6,7, - A Survey of Medical Education in Uruguay... in Brazil, June 1953, September 1955 (Box 002A, Folder 16)
    - Bauer, J. H. - Med Surv-1 - A Survey of Medical Education in Chile, May 1952 (Box 002A, Folder 0016A)
    - Bauer, J. H. - Med Surv-2,3,4, - A Survey of Medical Education in Ecuador,... Bolivia,... Peru, August-September 1952 (Box 002A, Folder 0016B)
    - Bauer, J. H. - Med Surv-5, - A Survey of Medical Education in Colombia, December 1952 (Box 002A, Folder 0016C)
    - Bauer, J. H. - Med Surv-6,7, - A Survey of Medical Education in Uruguay... in Brazil, June 1953, September 1955 (Box 002A, Folder 16)
    - Pan American Federation of Medical Schools, 1960-1070, 1972-1973 (Box 3, Folder 17-21)
    - Pan American Federation of Medical Schools - "Programa - Centros Multinaciones de Adiestromiento Avanzado en Ciencias Bio-Medicas para Profesores Investigadores", April 1970 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Pan American Federation of Medical Schools - Conference - (Grant in Aid), 1963-1965 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Pan American Federation of Medical Schools - Medical Educators Conference - (Grant in Aid; population program), 1968-1969 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Pan American Federation of Medical Schools - Regional Centers - (General Support), 1967-1972 (Box 4, Folder 25-26)
    - Pan American Federation of Medical Schools - Regional Centers - Reports, 1967-1968; 2 Items (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Pan American Federation of Medical Schools - (Grant in Aid), 1961-1963 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Program and Policy - (Medical Education), 1938, 1940-1941, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Pan American Federation of Medical Schools, 1964-1965, 1967 (Box 16, Folder 122)
  - Latin America - Natural Science, 300.D
    - Agricultural Education Center - (General Support), 1952-1955 (Box 4, Folder 30-31)
    - Agricultural Education Center - (General Support), 1956-1957, 1959-1960 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Agricultural Scholarships - Villena, Guillermo, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Borlaug, Norman E. - BORLAUG - Report on South American Trip, November - December 1952 (Box 5, Folder 0033A)
    - Corn Improvement - (Minutes), 1958-1962 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Corn Improvement, 1958-1964 (Box 5, Folder 35-38)
    - Instituto de Nutricion de Centro America y Panama - (Indigenous Crops Study), 1958-1960 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Instituto de Nutricion de Centro America y Panama - (Indigenous Crops Study), 1961-1965 (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - Instituto de Nutricion de Centro America y Panama - Corn Analysis - (Nevin Scrimshaw, Ricardo Bressani), 1954-1958, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 41-42)
    - Inter-American Association of Agricultural Librarians - Secretariat - (Service Extension), 1965-1972 (Box 6, Folder 43-46)
    - Inter-American Institute of Agricultural Sciences - Agricultural Directrors' Conference, 1964-1965 (Box 6, Folder 47)
    - Inter-American Institute of Agricultural Sciences - Agricultural Education - (Conference Attendance), 1957-1963 (Box 7, Folder 48-49)
    - Inter-American Institute of Agricultural Sciences - Alba, Jorge de (Animal Husbandry, Conference Attendance), 1962 (Box 7, Folder 50)
    - Inter-American Institute of Agricultural Sciences - Animal Husbandry (Diary Cattle Project), 1950-1963 (Box 7, Folder 51-52)
    - Inter-American Institute of Agricultural Sciences - Arias Segura, Carlos Luis - (Travel Grant), 1963-1969 (Box 7, Folder 53)
    - Inter-American Institute of Agricultural Sciences - Bean Improvement - (Grant in Aid), 1962-1963 (Box 7, Folder 54)
    - Inter-American Institute of Agricultural Sciences - Blair Fabris, Enrique - (Travel Grant, Agronomy), 1957-1958 (Box 7, Folder 55)
    - Inter-American Institute of Agricultural Sciences - Brazilian Library Development, 1966-1971 (Box 7, Folder 56)
    - Inter-American Institute of Agricultural Sciences - Corn Improvement, 1956-1959 (Box 7, Folder 57)
    - Inter-American Institute of Agricultural Sciences - Diaz Bordenave, Juan - (Agricultural Journalism), 1958-1959, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 58)
    - Inter-American Institute of Agricultural Sciences - Fonseca, Luiz - (Travel Grant, Agricultural Journalism), 1962-1963 (Box 8, Folder 59)
    - Inter-American Institute of Agricultural Sciences - Graduate School - (Teaching Equipment), 1955-1958 (Box 8, Folder 60)
    - Inter-American Institute of Agricultural Sciences - Gutierrez, Mario - (Maize Improvement), 1959, 1961-1964 (Box 8, Folder 61)
    - Inter-American Institute of Agricultural Sciences - Hopkins, John A. - (Farm Management), 1957-1961 (Box 8, Folder 62)
    - Inter-American Institute of Agricultural Sciences - Horticulture, 1957-1961 (Box 8, Folder 63)
    - Inter-American Institute of Agricultural Sciences - Latin American Conference, 1965-1969 (Box 8, Folder 64)
    - Inter-American Institute of Agricultural Sciences - Lendrayova, Olga - (Travel Grant, Librarian), 1961 (Box 8, Folder 65)
    - Inter-American Institute of Agricultural Sciences - Library - (Survey, Arthur Gropp and Ralph Shaw), 1948-1949 (Box 8, Folder 66-67)
    - Inter-American Institute of Agricultural Sciences - Library - (Survey, Arthur Gropp and Ralph Shaw), 1950-1956 (Box 9, Folder 68-73)
    - Inter-American Institute of Agricultural Sciences - Library Conference - (Purchase of Reference Materials), 1965-1969 (Box 9, Folder 74)
    - Inter-American Institute of Agricultural Sciences - Library Training, 1961-1965 (Box 10, Folder 75-76)
    - Inter-American Institute of Agricultural Sciences - Monge, Fernanado - (Travel Grant, Library Services), 1969-1970 (Box 10, Folder 77)
    - Inter-American Institute of Agricultural Sciences - Paladines, Osvaldo L. - (Travel Grant, Animal Husbandry), 1967 (Box 10, Folder 78)
    - Inter-American Institute of Agricultural Sciences - Plant Industry - (Purchase of Laboratory Equipment), 1958-1960 (Box 10, Folder 79)
    - Inter-American Institute of Agricultural Sciences - Pomology Symposium - (Grant in Aid, Participants' Travel), 1962-1963 (Box 10, Folder 80)
    - Inter-American Institute of Agricultural Sciences - Potato Program - (Casseres, E. H., Horticulture), 1954-1958 (Box 10, Folder 81)
    - Inter-American Institute of Agricultural Sciences - Program Review - (Biological Sciences Review Team and Panel), 1960-1962 (Box 10, Folder 82-83)
    - Inter-American Institute of Agricultural Sciences - Samper, Armando - (Travel Grant, Library Survey), 1962-1963 (Box 11, Folder 84)
    - Inter-American Institute of Agricultural Sciences - Temperature Zone Agriculture - (Elgueta, Manuel), 1956-1959 (Box 11, Folder 85)
    - Inter-American Institute of Agricultural Sciences - Tropical Crops, 1955-1959 (Box 11, Folder 86)
    - Inter-American Symposia on Plant Breeding, 1949-1955 (Box 11, Folder 87-90)
    - Inter-American Symposia on Plant Breeding, 1956-1962 (Box 12, Folder 91-92)
    - Inter-American Symposia on Plant Breeding - Visits, 1961 (Box 12, Folder 93)
    - Latin American Association of Plant Science - Gutierrez Jimenez, Mario - (Travel Grant, Agronomy), 1962-1964 (Box 12, Folder 94)
    - Latin American Association of Plant Science - Visits - (Mario Gutierrez Jimenez, Mathias Stelly), 1965-1966 (Box 12, Folder 95)
    - MIL-2 Miller, H. M. Jr. "First Survey Trip in Connection with Program in the National Sciences", July - November 1941 (Box 12, Folder 0095A)
    - Pan-American Conference of Veterinary Medicine, 1960-1963 (Box 12, Folder 96)
    - Potato Improvement - (Operating Program, Minutes), 1960-1965 (Box 12, Folder 97)
    - Potato Improvement - (Operating Program), 1958-1962 (Box 12, Folder 98-99)
    - Potato Improvement - (Operating Program), 1963-1966 (Box 13, Folder 100-102)
    - Program and Policy - (Natural Sciences), 1938, 1941-1943, 1946-1948, 1950-1955 (Box 13, Folder 103)
    - Program and Policy - Reports - PRO-1, 2, 3, 3A, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8 (Box 13, Folder 104-106)
    - Program and Policy - Agriculture - Reports, 1963, 1969; 2 Items (Box 14, Folder 108)
    - Program and Policy - Agriculture - Reports - PRO AGR - 1, 2 (Box 14, Folder 109)
    - Wheat Improvement - (Operating Program), 1958-1964 (Box 14, Folder 110-112)
    - BER-1 - Berrien, William - Record of Interviews, 1942-1944 (Box 15, Folder 113-114)
    - Inter-American Institute of Agricultural Sciences - Library - Financial Statement and Report, 1951 (Box 16, Folder 123)
    - Inter-American Symposia on Plant Breeding - Reports, 1955, 1961; 4 Items (Box 16, Folder 124)
    - Wheat Improvement - Reports, 1964; 4 Items (Box 16, Folder 125)
  - Latin America - Humanities and Arts, 300.R
    - BER-2 - Berrien, William - Report on Humanities in Mexico, Central and South America, October 31, 1944 (Box 15, Folder 115)
    - Program and Policy - (Humanities), 1937-1941, 1943 (Box 15, Folder 116)
    - Program and Policy - PRO-1, 2 - (Humanities) - Reports - (Fahs, Charles B.), 1951-1952; 2 Items (Box 15, Folder 117)
  - Latin America - Social Sciences, 300.S
    - Latin American Social Science Research Council - Data Archives - (Service Modernization), 1967-1972 (Box 15, Folder 118-119)
    - Program and Policy - (Social Sciences), 1938, 1940-1941, 1943-1944, 1958, 1960, 1963 (Box 15, Folder 120)
  - Latin America - Virus Studies, 300.V
    - SHO-1 Shope, R. B. "Diary of a Trip to Brazil and Colombia", November 10-16, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 121)
- Argentina, 1902-1972; 301; 12 box(es)
  Seven subseries as follows: 301 (no program letter; general material which does not fit into a particular program area) 301 A Medical sciences (research conducted in medical schools or medical research institutes, research directly applicable to the mental and physical health of human beings) 301 D Natural sciences and agriculture (research usually conducted in departments outside of medical schools, research in pure science, veterinary medicine or agriculture) 301 E Fellowships, scholarships, training awards 301 R Humanities and arts 301 S Social Sciences 301 V Virus Studies
  - Argentina - General (No Program), 301.GEN
    - University of Cuyo - Santamarina, Oscar - (Travel Grant, Electron Microscopy), 1959-1961 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Argentina - Medical Sciences, 301.A
    - Houssay, Bernardo A. - (Institute of Biology and Experimental Medicine), 1943-1949 (Box 1, Folder 2-8)
    - Houssay, Bernardo A. - (Institute of Biology and Experimental Medicine), 1950-1954, 1957-1958 (Box 2, Folder 9-10)
    - Institute of Biology (and Experimental Medicine) - Physiology - Annual Reports - (Juan H. Tramezzani, Jorge M. Affanni), 1959-1957, 1959-1964 (Box 2, Folder 11-12)
    - Institute of Biology (and Experimental Medicine) - Physiology - Annual Reports, 1945, 1946, 1956, 1958, 1961, 1962, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Institute of Medical Research - Rosario - (Lewis, Juan T.), 1948-1953, 1955-1958 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Medical Research - (National Council of Scientific and Technical Research) - (General Support), 1960-1965 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Medical Research - (National Council of Scientific and Technical Research) - Annual Reports, 1959, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - University of Buenos Aires - Cardiology - (Taquini, Alberto C.), 1956-1960 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - University of Buenos Aires - Cardiology - Reprints, 1949-1951, 1955-1958; 11 items (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - University of Buenos Aires - Clinical Medicine - (Lanari, Alfredo), 1956-1958 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - University of Buenos Aires - Mancini, Roberto E. - (Travel Grant, Histophysiology), 1957-1960 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - University of Buenos Aires - Physiology - Braun-Menendez, Edmondo, 1956-1958 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - University of Buenos Aires - Physiology - Personnel Training, 1957-1959 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - University of Cuyo - (School of Medicine, General Support), 1953, 1956-1957 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - University of Cuyo - (School of Medicine, General Support), 1958-1965 (Box 4, Folder 24-29)
    - University of Cuyo - (School of Medicine, General Support), 1966 (Box 5, Folder 30-31)
    - University of Cuyo - Aranguren, Jose Antonio - (Travel Grant, Heart Surgery), 1961-1964 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - University of Cuyo - Burgos, Mario H. - (Travel Grant, Cell Biology), 1959, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - University of Cuyo - Fasciolo, Juan Carlos - (Travel Grant, Physiology), 1956-1957 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - University of Cuyo - Itoiz, Juan Eleazar - (Travel Grant, Biochemistry), 1958 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - University of Cuyo - Muratorio Posse, Rodolfo - (Travel Grant, Clinical Medicine), 1957-1958 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - University of Cuyo - Suarez, Jorge R. E. - (Travel Grant, Medical Education Administration), 1956-1957 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - University of La Plata - Physiology - (Equipment Purchase), 1956-1960 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - University of La Plata - Rodreguiz, Ricardo Rosendo - (Travel Grant, Physiology), 1956-1957 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - University of Tucuman - (Institute of) High Altitude Biology - (Chiodi, Hugh), 1951, 1956-1958, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Institute of Biology - Physiology, 1951, 1958-1959 (Box 12, Folder 97)
    - Medical Research, 1960, 1964 (Box 12, Folder 98)
    - University of Cuyo, 1959, 1962-1964 (Box 12, Folder 99-100)
  - Argentina - Natural Sciences and Agriculture, 301.D
    - Godoy, Ernesto F. - (Travel Grant, Agronomy), 1956 (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - Institute of Biochemical Research - (Temporary Salary Support, Equipment and Supplies), 1964, 1967-1968 (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - Institute of Biochemical Research - Enzyme Chemistry - (Equipment and Supplies), 1958-1961 (Box 6, Folder 43)
    - Institute of Biochemical Research - Enzyme Chemistry - Reprints, 1948-1958; 37 items (Box 6, Folder 44)
    - Institute of Medical Research - Endocrinology - (Equipment and Supplies), 1957-1959 (Box 6, Folder 45)
    - Institute of Plant Science - (Equipment Purchase), 1956-1960 (Box 6, Folder 46-47)
    - Institute of Plant Science - Gomes, Frederico Pimentel - (Visiting Lecturer), 1960-1962 (Box 6, Folder 48)
    - National Institute of Agricultural Technology - Chabrillon, Alberyo Luis - (Travel Grant, Wheat Breeding Techniques), 1967 (Box 6, Folder 49)
    - National Institute of Agricultural Technology - Gutierrez, Manuel - (Travel Grant, Cotton Breeding), 1962-1964 (Box 6, Folder 50)
    - National Institute of Agricultural Technology - Induni, Cesar J. - (Travel Grant, Potato Breeding), 1965-1968 (Box 6, Folder 51)
    - National Institute of Agricultural Technology - Petersen, Benito - (Travel Grant, Wheat Breeding), 1962-1964 (Box 6, Folder 52)
    - National Institute of Agricultural Technology - Training Course - (Visiting Professors), 1962-1964 (Box 6, Folder 53)
    - National Institute of Agricultural Technology - Training Course - (Visiting Professors), 1965-1967 (Box 6, Folder 54)
    - National Institute of Agricultural Technology - Videla, Ramon Oscar - (Travel Grant, Soil Management), 1962-1963, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 55)
    - National Institute of Livestock Technology - Pasquale, Domingo R. - (Travel Grant, Training), 1962 (Box 7, Folder 56)
    - Pergamino Agricultural Experment Station - Godoy, Ernesto F. - (Travel Grant, Training), 1959-1963 (Box 7, Folder 57)
    - Pergamino Agricultural Experiment Station - Tombetta, Evito E. - (Travel Grant, Wheat Breeding), 1962-1963 (Box 8, Folder 58)
    - University of Buenos Aires - (Scientific Education), 1957, 1959-1964 (Box 8, Folder 59-64)
    - University of Buenos Aires - (Scientific Education), 1965-1968 (Box 8, Folder 65)
    - University of Buenos Aires - Camberos, Hector Remauldo - (Travel Grant, Veterinary Medicine), 1964-1965 (Box 8, Folder 66)
    - University of Buenos Aires - Enzyme Chemistry - (Stoppani, A. O. M.), 1956-1960 (Box 8, Folder 67)
    - University of Buenos Aires - Library, 1955-1957 (Box 8, Folder 68)
    - University of Buenos Aires - Microbiology - (Equipment Purchase), 1960-1961 (Box 8, Folder 69)
    - University of Cordoba - Pharmacology - (Landaburn, Ricardo), 1960-1965, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 70)
    - University of Cuyo - Tearo Metabolism - (Palleroni), 1958-1961 (Box 8, Folder 71)
    - Godsy, Ernesto F., 1956 (Box 12, Folder 101)
    - University of Buenos Aires, 1960, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 102)